Guide to the Magee Family Papers, 1790-1952 DAR.1968.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Watson Family Papers, 1795-1901; II.
  - Personal Papers of Jane Watson Magee, 1847-1880; 2.
    - Will of Jane Watson Magee, 1880 (Box 26, Folder 7)
- Receipts, 1790-1910; III.
  These receipts represent the domestic business of the Magee and Watson families. Receipts document the purchase of household goods and services such as food and utilities. Some of the Watson family receipts relate to monetary loans and money paid for rent. The receipts are arranged somewhat chronologically.
  - Receipts, 1790-1910 (Box 27, Folder 1-6)
  - Receipts, 1790-1910 (Box 28, Folder 1-7)
  - Receipts, 1790-1910 (Box 29, Folder 1-5)
  - Receipts, 1790-1910 (Box 30, Folder 1-7)
  - Receipts, 1790-1910 (Box 31, Folder 1-5)
- Family Material, Oversized, 1791-1880; IV.
  This series contains both Watson and Magee family material. All of the material is housed and an oversized box. The material consists of ephemera, certificates, degrees, sketches, drawings, deeds, estate plans, and ledgers. The majority of the material relates to Andrew Watson and his land and plot plans from 1791 to 1843. The material in this series dates from 1791 to 1906.
  - Biography of Pennsylvania, 1906 (Map-case 14, Drawer 11, Oversize 1)
  - J.W. Kerr architectural drawings for a summer house, undated (Oversize 2, Unknown item 2)
  - Spectacles, undated (Oversize 3)
  - Elizabeth Louise McLeod Magee's Bible, 1858 (Box 32)
    Scope and Contents
    The Holy Bible, Old and New Testaments, Translated out of The Original Tongues; and with the Former Translations Diligently Compared and Revised. New York: American Bible Society,1858.
    This volume was presented to Elizabeth Louise McLeod on January 12, 2859, the day of her marriage to Christopher L. Magee, by her father Rev. Dr. John Niel McLeod.
    The volume contains marriage, birth, and death records for the immediate family of Elizabeth L. McLeod (1836-1902) and Christopher L. Magee (1829-1909). The year of Elizabeth L. McLeod Magee's death is listing in the Bible as 1892, which appears to be incorrect. She died in 1902 according to many other sources.
  - Certificate to practice law in Allegheny County, April 11, 1852 (Oversize 5)
  - Certificate to practice law in the District Court of Philadelphia, December 18, 1852 (Oversize 6)
  - Christopher Magee appointment to Court of Common Pleas No. 2 of the Fifth Judicial District of Allegheny County, October 7, 1885 (Oversize 7)
  - Christopher Magee election to Court of Common Pleas No. 2 of the Fifth Judicial District of Allegheny County, December 17, 1886 (Oversize 8)
  - Christopher Magee, Jr., Law Degree, 1892 (Oversize 9)
  - University degree, undated (Oversize 10)
  - University degree, undated (Oversize 11)
  - University of Pennsylvania degree, undated (Oversize 12)
  - University degree, undated (Oversize 13)
  - Certificate to practice law in the Court of Common Pleas of Philadelphia, undated (Oversize 14)
  - Headstone design, undated (Oversize 15)
  - Poster, Steamship RR Agent, undated (Oversize 16)
  - Andrew Watson deed, April 9, 1791 (Oversize 17)
  - Andrew Watson land indenture, October 19, 1792 (Oversize 18)
  - Andrew Watson deed, 1795 (Oversize 19)
  - James McKinney deed, January 8, 1796 (Oversize 20)
  - Andrew Watson's license to open a public house, March 7, 1796 (Oversize 21)
  - Andrew Watson's appointment as Justice of the Peace, April 1798 (Oversize 22)
  - Robert Watson land purchase agreement, February 2, 1810 (Oversize 23)
  - Road Plan, August 5, 1810 (Oversize 24)
  - Robert Watson, Certificate to practice law in Allegheny County, 1824 (Oversize 25)
  - Plan of lots laid off by Andrew Watson, December 18, 1837 (Oversize 26)
  - Robert Watson, Passport, 1843 (Oversize 27)
  - Proposed plan of lots for commissioned for Andrew Watson, October 30, 1844 (Oversize 28)
  - Partition of land annexed by the District Court of Allegheny County, 1848 (Oversize 29)
  - Plan of the Watson Estate, 1849 (Oversize 30)
  - Robert Watson, Passport, 1865 (Oversize 31)
  - Partition of the Estate of Robert Watson, 1875 (Oversize 32)
  - Copy of P. H. Parson's survey of Black family property, undated (Oversize 33)
  - Plan of ground of Robert Watson, undated (Oversize 34)
  - Perpetual Lease to Robert Watson, undated (Oversize 35)
  - Plan of Wylie and Tunnel Streets with rail lines, undated (Oversize 36)
  - Map of public road with family lots, undated (Oversize 37)
  - Unnamed land plot diagram, undated (Oversize 38)
  - Ledger, undated (Oversize 39)
  - Ledger, undated (Oversize 40)
  - Cloth backed map of Pittsburgh, undated (Oversize 41)
  - Plan of Andrew Watson farm, copy 1, undated (Oversize 42)
  - Plan of Andrew Watson farm, copy 2, undated (Oversize 43)
  - Plan of William Watson properties, undated (Oversize 44)
  - Mortgage of James R. Irwin, September 17, 1834 (Oversize 45)
  - Plan of lots belonging to Jane Watson, April 1841 (Oversize 46)
  - Real estate of Jane Magee, deceased, 1880 (Oversize 47)
  - Plan of property in the Fifth Ward of Pittsburgh, undated (Oversize 48)
- Photographic Materials, 1850-1915; V.; 13.84 Linear Feet
  The extensive photographic materials in this collection consist of 19 boxes. The photographs depict the Magee family in their homes, during their travels, and in recreational settings such as the beach and the park. Specific locations include the Panama Canal, the western United States, England, and Kyoto, Japan. Walter Magee, in particular, is documented from infancy through adolescence, to his years at university, through a series of cabinet cards and prints. Many other family members are also identified in the photographs. A particular strength of this collection is in the broad variety of photographic formats and processes present. Among these are: daguerreotypes; ambrotypes; tintypes; cabinet cards; glass plate negatives; nitrate negatives; albumen prints; cyanotypes; and carte de visite. Several photograph albums are also included which contain cabinet cards and tintypes. Framed prints are also present.